pctools.com 2016-02-01

# PC Tools Privacy Policy

## Pctools.com Privacy Policy

Last updated 2012, 7 May

This policy sets out PC Tools S.à.r.l.'s and its affiliated companies (collectively, "PC Tools") privacy practices in connection with all of the products, services and websites offered by PC Tools (collectively, "services").

If you have any questions about this policy, are concerned about how personal data is processed by PC Tools, or if you wish to receive a copy of any personal data which you may have supplied to PC Tools, please feel free to contact us through our website or write to us at PC Tools S.à.r.l., c/- PO Box 1974, North Sydney NSW 2060, Australia.

### General statement

PC Tools fully respects your right to privacy, and will not collect any personal information about you without your clear permission. Any personal information which you volunteer to PC Tools will be treated with the appropriate standards of security and confidentiality, strictly in accordance with the applicable data protection regulations.

### Collection and use of personal information

PC Tools does not collect any personal data about you on this website or in connection with any other service, apart from information which you volunteer (for example by e-mailing us, by purchasing a product from us, by downloading a product from us, or by registering your product with us, or by using our online feedback form). When you purchase a product from PC Tools, we may collect information including your contact details and credit card details. Please note that credit card information may be retained by us or our billing provider as a record of any transaction we undertake with you.

Information which you provide is used by PC Tools only in line with the purpose for which you provided it and will not be made available to third parties, other than information provided to us during the purchase process which may be provided to our online billing provider and our banking institution to enable the purchase to be processed. Please note that the transfer of information by us to such third parties may involve a transfer of that information to countries outside Ireland or the EU.

If PC Tools has your email address, we may contact you by email to advise you of product updates, subscribe you to our newsletter or offer you PC Tools or third party products. You can opt out from receiving these emails at any time. Your preferences can be updated online by clicking here. PC Tools may also contact you in relation to customer support queries which you lodge. 

Your personal data may also be anonymised and used for statistical purposes.

### Your rights regarding data supplied to PC Tools

You have a right to be given a copy of any personal data which you may have supplied to PC Tools in connection with any service. To exercise this right, you must contact us through our website or write to us at PC Tools S.à.r.l., c/- PO Box 1974, North Sydney NSW 2060, Australia. If you are contacting us by mail, you should include any personal identifiers which you supplied earlier (e.g. name, address, phone number, e-mail address). Your request will be dealt with as soon as possible and will take not more than 40 days to process.

You also have a right to have any inaccurate information corrected. If you discover that PC Tools does hold inaccurate information about you, you have a right to instruct PC Tools to correct that information. Such instruction must be in writing or via e-mail. Your request will be dealt with as soon as possible and will take not more than 40 days to process.

In certain circumstances you may also request that data which you have supplied to PC Tools be deleted. To exercise this right you would generally be expected to identify some contravention of data protection law in the manner in which PC Tools processes the data concerned. Please note that PC Tools may from time to time delete data which it holds about you or other persons where PC Tools considers it appropriate to do so.

If you are concerned about how personal data is processed by PC Tools, please do not hesitate to bring such concerns to the attention of PC Tools at the contact details set out above.

### Collection and use of technical information

This website does use cookies - a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer to identify your browser - including temporary "session" cookies which enable a visitor's web browser to remember which pages on this website have already been visited and to track any referrer or affiliate information. Visitors can use this website with no substantial loss of functionality if cookies are disabled from the web browser.

Technical details in connection with visits to our website and our products may be logged by us or a third party for our statistical purposes and may also be used by our online billing provider to determine the purchase price during the purchase process. No information (apart from product purchase information) is collected that could be used by us to identify website visitors. The technical details logged are confined to the following types of information:

  * the Internet Protocol address or gateway of the visitor's web server
  * the previous website address from which the visitor reached us
  * clickstream data which shows the traffic of visitors around this web site (for example pages accessed and documents downloaded)
  * the type of web browser used by the visitor
  * the operating system of the visitor's computer
  * the screen resolution of the visitor's computer monitor
  * information on potential security risks, URLs of websites visited that PC Tools software deems potentially fraudulent and portable executable files that are identified as potential malware
  * information regarding installation of PC Tools' software and other general, statistical information used for license administration, product analysis, and for improving product functionality. 

By supplementing our records, this information helps us learn things like: whether installation of our software was successfully completed; what pages are most attractive to our visitors; which of our products most interest our customers; what kinds of offers our customers like to see; evaluating and improving the ability of our products to detect malicious behavior, potentially fraudulent websites and other internet security risks and how to improve the ability of our products to detect malicious behavior. Where a third party logs information on our behalf, we control how that data may and may not be used. 

PC Tools will make no attempt to identify individual visitors, or to associate the technical details listed above with any individual. It is PC Tools' policy never to disclose such technical information in respect of individual website visitors to any third party (apart from any third party providing services to us which may record, process or analyse such data on our behalf and which is bound by confidentiality provisions in this regard), unless obliged or permitted to disclose such information by a rule of law.

The technical information will be used only by PC Tools, and only for statistical and other administrative purposes. You should note that technical details, which we cannot associate with any identifiable individual, do not constitute "personal data" for the purposes of the Data Protection Acts, 1988 & 2003.

### Other websites

PC Tools is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites accessible from this website via external links. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. Any external links to other websites are clearly identifiable as such.

### Cookies on PCTools.com

The cookies used on this site are described according to the following cookie categories based on the International Chamber of Commerce guide for cookies:

  * Strictly Necessary
  * Performance
  * Functionality
  * Targeting 

### STRICTLY NECESSARY COOKIES

These cookies do not collect any information about you that could be used for marketing purposes or to track your navigation on other websites.

### Purposes

We use Strictly Necessary Cookies for the following purposes:

  * Differentiate you from other users on the site, and provide you the appropriate content you requested
  * Prevent fraud transactions in the shopping cart
  * Provide VeriSign Trust Seal in the shopping cart 

### List of Strictly Necessary Cookies (First Party)

ASP.NET_SessionId  
PHPSESSID  
thx_guid  
v1st  

### PERFORMANCE COOKIES

These cookies do not collect any information about you that could be used for marketing purposes, to track your navigation on other websites, or to send you targeted ads. These cookies collect information about how visitors use our website, for instance which pages they go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These are only used to improve how a website works.

### Purposes

We use Performance Cookies for the following purposes:

  * Perform Web Analytics, including determining service performance and counting number of visitors to our sites, pages that referred you to our sites, etc
  * Establish and continue sessions
  * Perform A/B testing of web pages

You can opt out from these cookies by adjusting your browser settings to reject cookies. If you have previously visited our websites, you may also have to delete any existing cookies from your browser. Also, you can opt out from Omniture cookies at: [http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/2o7#optout.](http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/2o7#optout)

### List of Performance Cookies (First Party):

__utma  
__utmb  
__utmc  
__utmz  
buySAFEUID  
mbox  
s_pers  
s_sess   
s_sv_112_p1  
s_sv_112_s1  
s_vi  

### Third Party Performance Cookies

### FUNCTIONALITY COOKIES

We do not use functionality cookies to target you with advertisements on other websites. These cookies allow the website to detect some features of your device, for instance if you are using a mobile to navigate, and to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies can be used to remember changes made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that can be customized. They may also be used to provide services you asked for such as watching a video, initiating a chat, or commenting on a blog. These cookies cannot track browsing activity on other websites.

### Purposes

We use functionality cookies for the following purposes:

  * Provide proactive chat sessions
  * Limit proactive chat sessions
  * Identify when you have clicked on the chat button
  * Deliver appropriate chat content to you
  * Use the appropriate language for chat based on your Geo IP location
  * Maintain chat history for the session
  * Identify when you initiated the last chat 
  * Provide customer support forum functionality, including identifying when you are active on the forum, which session is yours, on which page and at what time 

Some of these cookies are managed for us by third parties. You can control the use of these cookies, but if you opt out from them, we may be unable to offer some services or support and we may also be unable to remember that you did not want a certain service.

### List of Functionality Cookies (First Party):

bb_lastactivity  
bb_lastvisit  
bb_sessionhash  
checkout  
IS3_History  
IS3_GSV  
isvt_visitor  
LastVisit  
mlaccepted  
mlreferer  

### TARGETING COOKIES

Targeting cookies on our sites are linked to services provided by third parties. Our third party provides these services in return for recognising that you have visited our website. 

### Purposes

We use targeting cookie for the following purposes:

  * Identify which pages you have used and found helpful, while on our websites

### List of Targeting Cookies (First Party):

reftrack

### Changes to this policy

Please note that PC Tools may change this policy from time to time. Any amended policy terms will be posted to the PC Tools website.
